Carl James Nicholls

9D Claremont Road, Surbiton, Surrey, KT6 4TN

07712 450885



carljnicholls@hotmail.com

Personal Statement

I am full stack software developer with experience in .NET, OO, Node.js, Microsoft Azure, JavaScript, Bootstrap 3 and mini.css. In my personal development projects, I enjoy taking an Agile approach to development and to use methodologies such as TDD and design patterns such as MVC and multi-tier architectures. I have experience with Visual Studio 2015-17 as well as text editors such as Atom and Visual Studio Code. This adaptability to different environments displays my ability to learn and overcome issues associated with different forms of development on different locations within the hardware stack. Having just finished studying at the University of Plymouth with a result of a first-class degree with honours. I am hoping to start an interesting career in bleeding edge technologies and .NET framework.

Key Modules/Skills

Computing Project (Multiple Tier Microsoft Azure Web Application)

ASP.net, T-SQL, Node.js, WebRTC, Moment.js, Bootstrap, Visual Studio 2015-17, Visual Studio Code, MSTest, QUnit, Hashing Functions, signalmaster NPM library utilising Googles public STUN servers.

Key Responsibilities

- Use of Visual Studio Team Services for GIT control, backlog and task management.
- UI design and implementation conforming to best practices.
- Organisation of stakeholder meetings.
- Database design and implementation.
- API development.
- Client side development.
- User feedback and testing.
- Implementing Unit tests at the end of sprints to prevent feature regression.

Client-Side Web Scripting (Location-based social networking web app)

Node.js, Express.js, Google Maps Geolocation API, JS-SHA256 NPM library, Bootstrap 3, QUnit, TDD

Key Responsibilities

- End to end full stack development.
- Secure storage and management of private API keys.
- Github version control.
- Writing unit tests.

Object Orientated Programming (Emergency Site Register)

Java Web Application, TDD, MVC, Javadoc, JUnit, Third party Java libraries, Design Patterns, SOLID principles

Key Responsibilities

- End to end full stack development.
- Design and implementation of design patterns.
- Data structure class library separation of concerns.
- Github version control.
- Using TDD to confirm no regressions.

Employment History

Waiter – Retro Bistrot (Nov 2013 – Dec 2015)

Working at Retro Bistrot I had to give a high standard of personal service, showing initiative and a high level of observation which allows me to deconstruct processes. I was often left to organise small teams to ensure good service.

Food and Beverage Supervisor – The Park Hotel (June 2011 – Oct 2013)

Working for the Park Hotel I was responsible for the day to day running, stocktaking, and organisation for Bar & waiting staff.

Education

Plymouth University 2015 – 2017

First Class Honours in BSc Computing

Modules

- Computing Project
- Work Based learning
- Internet Psychology and Persuasive Technology
- Client-Side web scripting
- Software Project Management
- Computing Integrating Project
- Mobile Device programming
- Secure Systems Architectures and Mechanisms
- User-Centred Interface Design
- Database Applications Development
- Object Oriented Programming

Kingston College 2013 – 2015

Merit in HND Computing and Systems Development

Truro & Penwith College 2006 – 2008

Merit in National Diploma in Media

Mounts Bay School and Community Sports College

2001 – 2006

10 GCSE's, Grades A – C including English, Mathematics and Science

Interests & Extra Curricular Activities

I enjoy researching bleeding edge technologies, discussing their use, models of interaction and the implications of them. I also enjoy current scientific and technological news but when away from an internet connection, I also appreciate nature and enjoy spending time disconnected and going for walks. I often spend free time reading and playing around with new technologies.

References, Module Results and further information available upon request